<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Stephen Ross</title>
    <link>http://localhost:1313/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Stephen Ross</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-ca</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 16:55:18 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="http://localhost:1313/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Alfred Brendel, 1931-2025</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/brendel/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Jun 2025 16:55:18 -0400</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/brendel/</guid>
      <description>Today I heard that Alfred Brendel passed away. His recordings of Schubert, Beethoven and Mozart are some of my favourites, but he was also a keen writer and critic. His essays are just as worth reading as his recordings are worth listening. So in remembrance, I thought I&amp;rsquo;d share a bit of the opening to &amp;ldquo;Schubert&amp;rsquo;s Last Sonatas.&amp;rdquo;&#xA;Schubert&amp;rsquo;s death deprived us of a wealth of possible masterpieces, though hardly, as Franz Grillparzer&amp;rsquo;s epitaph suggests, of even fairer accomplishment.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Science and Art</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/posts/science-and-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 19:58:13 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/posts/science-and-art/</guid>
      <description>These are some stray thoughts on the relationship between science and art. If I had enough time, they would form the kernel of a larger essay. I still wrote them anyway, because at least then I might end up picking the thread up again later! They are in decent enough shape as is that I don&amp;rsquo;t mind sharing them here.&#xA;1. It&amp;rsquo;s tempting to think that science and art have little to do with each other.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Academics</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/academics/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/academics/</guid>
      <description>You can see my CV here.&#xA;And you can contact me at rosss23@mcmaster.ca&#xA;Doctoral Candidate I am a doctoral candidate in philosophy at McMaster University under the supervision of Dr. Alex Klein.&#xA;Dissertation Research: How far can we tolerate or encourage differences between scientific representations? When do differences become conflicts which researchers need to resolve? Some scientific pluralists walk a tightrope, trying to allow as many differences to coexist as possible without tarnishing science&amp;rsquo;s objectivity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stephen Ross</title>
      <link>http://localhost:1313/about/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>http://localhost:1313/about/</guid>
      <description>I&amp;rsquo;m a Canadian philosophy student nearing the end of my PhD, and a classical musician (I play the piano).&#xA;What is this website for? It&amp;rsquo;s partly an alternative to having social media profiles. But I also want to write here. As a friend of mine put it:&#xA;This is gonna sound corny and hippie as all hell but I think there’s something to say for a travelogue of the mind, dude.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
