<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Philosophy on Stephen Ross</title>
    <link>https://stephenagross.ca/tags/philosophy/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Philosophy on Stephen Ross</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://stephenagross.ca/tags/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Science and Art</title>
      <link>https://stephenagross.ca/posts/science-and-art/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2025 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://stephenagross.ca/posts/science-and-art/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;These are some stray thoughts on the relationship between science and art. If I had enough time, they would form the kernel of a larger essay. I still wrote them anyway, because at least then I might end up picking the thread up again later! They are in decent enough shape as is that I don&amp;rsquo;t mind sharing them here.&lt;/p&gt;&#xA;&lt;h3 id=&#34;1&#34;&gt;1.&lt;/h3&gt;&#xA;&lt;p&gt;It’s tempting to think that science and art have little to do with each other. Science unveils reality, while art expresses human creativity. Of course, even on such a view, there is some comparison. Both involve making and improving something: in their daily work, scientists write and revise much as creative writers do, or repair and calibrate equipment much as an artist or musician would in their studio. Many of the basic activities in science and art resemble each other. There have also been historical episodes where science and art overlapped: think of harmony and mathematics in ancient Greece, or the geometry of linear perspective in Renaissance Italy, or photography in the 19th century, or data visualisation in today’s cosmology and astronomy. But perhaps these connections are superficial. Aren’t the aims of science and art are fundamentally different? Truth is objective, while the aims of art are subjective. They might borrow tools from each other like neighours, applying scientific procedures to artistic work, or artistic techniques to advance scientific research.&lt;sup id=&#34;fnref:1&#34;&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;#fn:1&#34; class=&#34;footnote-ref&#34; role=&#34;doc-noteref&#34;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; But in science those tools enable discovery, whereas in art they spur invention. So it cannot follow that science and art share a deeper connection.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
